<dc:title>Putting the DSA into Practice: Enforcement, Access to Justice, and Global Implications</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoboken, Joris van</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Buri, Ilaria</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Quintais, João Pedro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fahy, Ronan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Appelman, Naomi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Straub, Marlene</dc:creator>
<dc:type>collection</dc:type>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.17176/20230208-093135-0</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>https://intr2dok.vifa-recht.de/receive/</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>https://intr2dok.vifa-recht.de/receive/mir_mods_00015033</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Europarecht</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ddc:340</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Verfassungsbooks on Matters Constitutional</dc:subject>
<dc:description>The publication of the Digital Services Act in the Official Journal marks the end of a years-long drafting and negotiation process, and opens a new chapter: that of its enforcement, practicable access to justice, and potential to set global precedents. The Act has been portrayed as Europe’s new ‘Digital Constitution’, which affirms the primacy of democratic rulemaking over the private transnational ordering mechanisms of Big Tech. With it, the European Union aims once again to set a global standard in the regulation of the digital environment. But will the Digital Services Act be able to live up to its expectations, and under what conditions? Martin Husovec Will the Digital Services Act Work?: On Money and Effort Folkert Wilman Between Preservation and Clarification: The Evolution of the DSA's Liability Rules in Light of the CJEU's Case Law Sebastian Becker and Jan Penfrat The DSA Fails to Reign in the Most Harmful Digital Platform Businesses – But It Is Still Useful Alexandra Geese Why the DSA Could Save Us From the Rise of Authoritarian Regimes Ilaria Buri A Regulator Caught Between Conflicting Policy Objectives: Reflections on the European Commission ́s Role as DSA Enforcer Julian Jaursch Platform Oversight: Here is what a Strong Digital Services Coordinator Should Look Like Alessandro Mantelero Fundamental Rights Impact Assessment in the DSA Asha Allen An Intersectional Lens on Online Gender-Based Violence and the Digital Services Act Catalina Goanta Now What: Exploring the DSA's Enforcement Futures in Relation to Social Media Platforms and Native Advertising Pietro Ortolani If You Build it, They Will Come: The DSA “Procedure Before Substance” Approach Aleksandra Kuczerawy Remedying Overremoval Tomiwa Ilori Contextualisation over Replication: The Possible Impacts of the Digital Services Act on Content Regulation in African Countries Nayanatara Ranganathan Regulating Influence, Timidly Nicolo Zingales The DSA as a Paradigm Shift for Online Intermediaries' Due Diligence: Hail To Meta-Regulation Daphne Keller The European Union's New Digital Services Act and the Rest of the World</dc:description>
<dc:description>Die Veröffentlichung des Gesetzes über digitale Dienste im Amtsblatt markiert das Ende eines jahrelangen Entwurfs- und Verhandlungsprozesses und schlägt ein neues Kapitel auf: das seiner Durchsetzung, des praktikablen Zugangs zur Justiz und des Potenzials, weltweite Präzedenzfälle zu schaffen. Das Gesetz wurde als Europas neue „digitale Verfassung“ bezeichnet, die den Vorrang der demokratischen Regelsetzung vor den privaten transnationalen Ordnungsmechanismen von Big Tech bekräftigt. Damit will die Europäische Union einmal mehr einen globalen Standard für die Regulierung des digitalen Umfelds setzen. Doch wird das Gesetz über digitale Dienste die Erwartungen erfüllen können, und unter welchen Bedingungen? Martin Husovec Will the Digital Services Act Work?: On Money and Effort Folkert Wilman Between Preservation and Clarification: The Evolution of the DSA's Liability Rules in Light of the CJEU's Case Law Sebastian Becker and Jan Penfrat The DSA Fails to Reign in the Most Harmful Digital Platform Businesses – But It Is Still Useful Alexandra Geese Why the DSA Could Save Us From the Rise of Authoritarian Regimes Ilaria Buri A Regulator Caught Between Conflicting Policy Objectives: Reflections on the European Commission ́s Role as DSA Enforcer Julian Jaursch Platform Oversight: Here is what a Strong Digital Services Coordinator Should Look Like Alessandro Mantelero Fundamental Rights Impact Assessment in the DSA Asha Allen An Intersectional Lens on Online Gender-Based Violence and the Digital Services Act Catalina Goanta Now What: Exploring the DSA's Enforcement Futures in Relation to Social Media Platforms and Native Advertising Pietro Ortolani If You Build it, They Will Come: The DSA “Procedure Before Substance” Approach Aleksandra Kuczerawy Remedying Overremoval Tomiwa Ilori Contextualisation over Replication: The Possible Impacts of the Digital Services Act on Content Regulation in African Countries Nayanatara Ranganathan Regulating Influence, Timidly Nicolo Zingales The DSA as a Paradigm Shift for Online Intermediaries' Due Diligence: Hail To Meta-Regulation Daphne Keller The European Union's New Digital Services Act and the Rest of the World</dc:description>
<dc:date>2023</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>Verfassungsbooks</dc:publisher>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>info:eu-repo/semantics/restrictedAccess</dc:rights>